Ollie Wright

Game Designer/Programmer

Portfolio: https://ollieswright02.wixsite.com/portfolio/portfolio

GitHub: https://github.com/OllieGuy

PROFILE

As a game designer with 6 years of experience with game creation, and 15 years of gaming (specifically open world and first person shooter games), I have a keen interest in game development, spending much of my free time carrying out research on game design principles, through reviewing essays and articles, as well as watching videos made by creators such as Game Maker's Toolkit and Writing on Games. I am also a very sociable person, being part of my university's esports society, and thrive in team based environments.

EXPERIENCE

Press Space, University Project — Solo (design, code, art)

February 2023 - May 2023

Press Space is a satirical branching narrative game, featuring nine different endings. The game was designed to critique the relationship between players and developer, as well as the concept of free will within games

Skills: Design for game feel, C#, Narrative experience, Branching stories

GOLDRUSH, University Project — Solo (code, design, art)

October 2022 - December 2022

GOLDRUSH was a solo project, a 2d top down shooter game with player given parameter-based random level generation, a dynamic camera, and UI system as well as enemy AI based on a finite state machine. C# program, using Unity Skills: Unity, C#, Finite State Machines, Object Oriented Programming

Cedrik's Crown, University Project — Lead Designer & QA

October 2022 - January 2023

Cedrik's Crown is a 2-4 player dungeon crawler RPG board game. The enemy encounters were balanced by a program written by myself in C#. I focused mostly on the core gameplay loop and the player experience, in addition to playtesting extensively in order to ensure balance and player engagement being retained Skills: understanding of design principles and balancing, team leadership, C#, C++

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth — working towards a BSc in Computer Games Technology — September 2021 - Present

Undergraduate working on a BSc in Computer Games Technology 1st year - Received a First 2nd year - Received a First

The Henley College, Henley — A-Levels – May 2021

Maths (A) Economics (A) Computer Science (A)

26 Norman Road PO4 0LP

ollieswright02@gmail.com

PROGRAM PROFICIENCY

Visual Studio 2019 and 2022 Unity & PlasticSCM

C#

C++

Git

GitHub

Microsoft Office suite Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro Aseprite

SKILLS

Working with teams

Meeting and engaging with new people

Effective communication with co-workers and clients

Strong work ethic and willingness to learn

Positive attitude/outlook and enthusiastic approach

QUALIFICATIONS

Archery Level 1 Coaching Award 2016

Work Experience at the SAE Institute of Technology and Media 2018

INTERESTS

Game Development
Game Design
Artificial intelligence/machine
learning
Media Theory
Gaming